Viddy Rizkiyansah

Sales & Business Development Manager at Zamasco Mitra Solusindo, PT

che_dots@yahoo.com

Experience

Sales and Business Development Manager at Zamasco Mitra Solusindo, PT

May 2016 - Present (3 months)

IT companies that have services of hardware, software and custom integrated system.

What i do:

- 1. Analyze existing products with SWOT and 4P
- 2. Develop existing products
- 3. Developing new products
- 4. Brand awareness
- 5. Marketing function
- 6. Creating cooperation with a reseller
- 7. Execute operational branding and marketing
- 8. Data mining
- 9. Sales Lead
- 10. Tailored Presentation
- 11. Presentation with management and commissioners
- 12. Sell existing products
- 13. Making digital campaign materials
- 14. Conduct a simple design with photoshop
- 15. Business Development Function

Achievement:

- a. Collection database corresponding to the desired customer profile
- b. Increase the chances of getting clients
- c. Collaborated with new reseller
- d. Strengthen the company through the linkedin and branding campaign via MailChimp

Founder at www.mycoffeetaste.com

July 2015 - Present (1 year 1 month)

Marketplace Roasted Coffee Beans from Indonesian Roaster

What i do:

- 1. Develop website
- 2. SEO

- 3. Maintenance Website
- 4. Operational
- 5. Google adwords
- 4. sell sell sell
- 5. Google Analytics
- 6. Social Media
- 7. Concept
- 8. Relationship
- 9. Merchant acquisitions
- 10. Selling Channel Marketplace
- 11. Content Marketing
- 12. CRM

Business Consultant at Marjin Kiri

September 2015 - March 2016 (7 months)

Book Publisher

What i do:

- 1. Develop website
- 2. SEO
- 3. Maintenance Website
- 4. Training
- 5. Google adwords
- 4. sell sell sell

Build the selling channel:

shop.marjinkiri.com

https://www.tokopedia.com/marjinkiri

https://www.bukalapak.com/marjinkiri

Senior National Account Manager at uitox global e-commerce group

April 2015 - March 2016 (1 year)

What i do:

- Handle customer and made business plan to create new marketplace
- Made Manual book for internal and external user
- Presentation the company services to client
- Solved problem on client side
- Handle internal marketplace system
- Give solution to client how to implemented digital marketing for their marketplace

- Google Adwords
- Google Analytics
- Facebook Ads
- Open new pipelines with digital agency
- Trainee the User
- Business Consultation for Client
- Open New Sales Channel for Client

Uitox is a global ecommerce company. Currently we operate in 8 different countries, such as Taiwan, China, Singapore, Hongkong, Japan, Malaysia, Indonesia and United States. As an eccomerce company, we operates different kind of business model such as B2C Marketplace, Ecommerce enabler (providing end to end ecommerce solution). The services we provide are ranging from online webstore creation, payment system, warehouse management system (which is our core), shipping logistic including tracking and also ecommerce operation.

Global e-commerce group, providing the following services in cities around the world.

1.E-commerce Total Solution

We provide e-commerce tools for brands and suppliers to build up their EC capabilities:

E-Commerce Warehouse Management Service.

E-Commerce Logistics Solution.

E-Commerce Payment Service.

Online Store Creation Service.

Embedded Shopping Cart in Vendors' Official Sites.

Daily E-Commerce Operations.

Cross-border Sales Service.

2.uitox-owned Local B2C Sites

Brands and suppliers can also sell through uitox-owned B2C sites. Our currently owned sites at Singapore Brand; Shanghai Brand; Taiwan Brand

3. Global Cross-border Shopping

Products in local uitox system can be sold through other uitox websites around the world:

Real time global inventory information

Orders can be place if item is in stock

Supplier's products can be sold globally

Co Founder at Witprabot

November 2014 - March 2016 (1 year 5 months)

www.witprabot.com

Reclaim Teak Wood

What i do:

- 1. Develop website
- 2. SEO
- 3. Maintenance Website
- 4. Operational
- 5. Google adwords
- 4. sell sell sell

Business Consultant at Magicinkmagz.com

May 2013 - March 2016 (2 years 11 months)

First Indonesian Tatto Magazines and what i do is:

- 1. Develop website
- 2. Google adsense
- 3. Maintenance Website

Account Manager at Dun and Bradstreet

July 2012 - April 2015 (2 years 10 months)

What i do:

- Generate sales for a portfolio of accounts and reach the company's sales target
- Identify new sales opportunities within existing accounts to remain a client-account manager relationship by up-selling and cross-selling
- Manage and solve conflicts and problems with clients
- Interact and coordinate with the sales team and other staff members in other departments
- Establish budgets with the client and company
- Delivering presentations and attending meetings with clients
- Maintaining good relationships with clients

Project Coordinator:

- PT. Perusahaan Listrik Negara (Persero) Vendor Assessment Financial Strength
- o PT PengembanganListrikNasional Geothermal
- o UIP PembangkitanHidroJawa Bali (UIP VI)
- o Wilayah Nusa Tenggara Barat
- o Wilayah Kalimantan Selatan dan Tengah
- o PT PelayananListrikNasionalTarakan
- o UIP TransmisiInterkoneksi Sumatera Jawa (UIP IV)
- o Distribusi DKI Jaya & Tangerang

- o Wilayah Kalimantan Timur
- o Wilayah Nusa Tenggara Timur
- o Wilayah Papua dan Papua Barat
- PT. Vale Indonesia Tbk Vendor Assessment Financial Strength
- PT. Sumitomo Heavy Industries Market research
- The Executive Centre database company
- Cisco Singapore cleansing data for lead sales
- User Experience and system for website Cyberqoute Indonesia, subsidiary of D&B Indonesia

Co Founder at Media Kreativa

September 2011 - January 2013 (1 year 5 months)

Our Services:

Website

- www.indonesianjassfestival.com
- www.zamasco.co.id
- www.http://linkedin.com/uas/security/general-malware?url=magicinkmagz.com
- www.jurnalline.com
- www.essencedarmawangsa.com
- www.mycoffeetaste.com

Server

- Maintenance, Migration, monitoring
- Webmail

Social Media Engagement

- Smarfren
- CoffeeTaste

Ios & Android Application

- Marketing tools ipad

Hosting and Domain

Our Klien:

- PT. Prakarsa Semesta Alam
- PT. Sali Gading Bersama
- PT. Zamasco Mitra Solusindo

Assisstant Production Manager at Indonesia Tatler and Group (PT Mobiliari Stephindo)

January 2012 - June 2012 (6 months)

What i do:

- 1. request a quotation from vendor printing
- 2. analyze the prices from vendors
- 3. supervising printing production (color, finishing, design etc)
- 4. coordinate with marketing for the placement of advertising pages
- 5. collecting written materials and advertising
- 6. Make an example of a print magazine

Manager Operational For Retail Printing at Reycom Printing Solusi

February 2010 - December 2011 (1 year 11 months)

What i do:

- Handle Projects Insurance Company
- Handle printing area from pre press process- finishing delivery report
- Manage and solve the client complaint and problems
- Delivering presentations and attending meetings with clients
- Monitoring and manage the production schedule in order to delivered the product in time
- Prepare the raw material base on forecast and manage the production line with production planning in the factory in order to match with customer needs

Planning - Production - Inventory Control - Delivery at Retail printing Coorporate customer such as; AXA - AXA Mandiri - Prudential - CIMB Sunlife - Freeport - Datindo - Equity - OCBC NISP

and many customer retail (individual)

Training Color and file prepress at PT. Astragraphia

Training color management digital printing machine at PT. Astragraphia

Standar Operation Procedur for production

Flow chart general scope (marketing - production - finance)

Accounting Stock Staff at PT. Centrado

October 2009 - February 2010 (5 months)

What i do:

- 1.Stock Opname (about 200 item)
- 2. Prepare the spare parts for stabilizer
- 3. Order the spare parts

Summary

INTRODUCTION

Information and Communication Technology has an important role in the development of an enterprise or government. To follow the development of the digital world is so fast and dynamic, required creativity and individual skills so as not to fall behind. Departure from these requirements, PT Mitra Solusindo Zamasco want to play in order to provide the best solution in order to support the company's strategy in the future.

PT Mitra Solusindo Zamasco collaboration with various business partners who are experienced and reliable in the field. Together with business partners who are actively involved in supporting the development of Information and Communication Technology industry, PT Mitra Solusindo Zamasco provide solutions that are divided into two categories, products and services. Business solutions implemented by PT Mitra Solusindo Zamasco support and development of the company's credibility in the present and in the future.

VISION

Being the best in providing IT solutions that support the business processes of an enterprise and become the company's most in demand by consumers who can provide a good product innovation and satisfying service.

MISSION

Consistently at the forefront of Information Technology, Communications and provide services and the right product to the consumer so as to improve and support the business processes of consumers.

Courses

Co Founder

Media Kreativa Website development

Senior National Account Manager

uitox global e-commerce group Google Mobile Leadership Program

Independent Coursework

Game Theory

Facebook Marketing Bootcamp

Languages

English

(Elementary proficiency)

Volunteer Experience

Network Investment at Global Entrepreneurship Program Indonesia

February 2015 - Present

Pendiri GEPI bukan hanya pemimpin bisnis sangat berpengaruh di Indonesia, tetapi juga individu - individu yang memiliki passion untuk entrepreneurship. Keberhasilan mereka adalah inspirasi bagi kami dan dukungan besar mereka berperan penting bagi perjalanan GEPI ke depan.

Honorary Chairman:

- 1. Ir. Ciputra
- 2. Jakob Oetama

Chairman: Chris Kanter

Coordinator at Food Not Bombs

2006 - Present

Projects

Vendor Selection System PT. PLN (Persero)

January 2014 to Present

Members: Viddy Rizkiyansah

PT Pengembangan Listrik Nasional Geothermal

UIP Pembangkitan Hidro Jawa Bali (UIP VI)

Wilayah Nusa Tenggara Barat

Wilayah Kalimantan Selatan dan Tengah

PT Pelayanan Listrik Nasional Tarakan

UIP Transmisi Interkoneksi Sumatera Jawa (UIP IV)

Distribusi DKI Jaya & Tangerang

Wilayah Kalimantan Timur

Wilayah Nusa Tenggara Timur

Wilayah Papua dan Papua Barat

Vendor Selection System PT. Vale Indonesia Tbk

Members: Viddy Rizkiyansah

Vendor Selection System PT. Vale Indonesia Tbk

Market Research

February 2014 to Present

Members: Viddy Rizkiyansah

Heavy Equipment Spareparts Survey

Education

Universitas Kristen Satya Wacana

bachelor, Accounting, 2004 - 2009

Grade: 0.9

Activities and Societies: Formal activities: Marketing Festival '05 - Enterpreneur '09 - Diskusi panel '09 - coordinator Point Card SEMA FE 2005 – 2006 - Seminar Nasional Akuntansi '07 - Workshop Dokumenter '07 (panitia) - Sekretaris Finger Kine Klub 2007 – 2008 - Save The Earth '05 - Down To The Stream '05 - Latihan Kepemimpinan Lembaga Kemahasiswaan UKSW - Non-Formal activities: Pilosophy discussion with Smell Salatiga - Food Not Bomb collective Salatiga - Film Independent Finger Kine Klub community Salatiga -

Interests

Read all kind of book

Sports

Traveling

Kuliner

Skills & Expertise

Marketing

Project Planning

Management

Business Planning

Retail

Business Strategy

Operations Management

Team Building

Microsoft Office

Cost Accounting

Microsoft Excel

Analysis

Data Analysis

Event Planning

Film

Inventory Management

Manufacturing

Negotiation

Photoshop

Teamwork

Vendor Management

Digital Printing

Software Documentation

Strategic Planning

Forecasting

Budgets

Google Analytics

Marketing Communications

Quality Control

Project Management

Digital Marketing

facebook ads

E-commerce

Google Adwords

Marketing Strategy

Business Development

social media campaign

Innovation

Problem Solving

Writing

Sales

New Business Development

Sales Management

Account Management

Strategy

Market Research

Key Account Management

B2B

Organizations

Finger Kine Klub

Sekretaris

2005 to Present

Honors and Awards

The Best of New Sales Contract

Dun and Bradstreet Indonesia

2013

Certifications

Google Analytics

Google Partner September 2015

Google Adwords Fundamental

Google partner October 2015

Viddy Rizkiyansah

Sales & Business Development Manager at Zamasco Mitra Solusindo, PT

che_dots@yahoo.com



Contact Viddy on LinkedIn